<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>COMP6[84]45 Slides</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on COMP6[84]45 Slides</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>09: devsecops</title><link>/week9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week9/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 dev sec ops 6[84]43 week9 My Experience How&amp;rsquo;d you find the course
What&amp;rsquo;d you like What&amp;rsquo;d you dislike What can be improved https://myexperience.unsw.edu.au
DevSecOps Waterfall &amp;#x1f30a; vs agile &amp;#x1f3c3; Systematic/design vulnerabilities are much harder to solve than simple coding/logic errors.
This is exacerbated in the waterfall approach, as you don&amp;rsquo;t really go back to the design phase.
Waterfall &amp;#x1f30a; exponentially more $$$ to fix bugs later into SDLC we want to shift security left &amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; &amp;#x1f4bb; vms vs containers &amp;#x1f433; CVEs</description></item><item><title>1: intro</title><link>/week1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week1/</guid><description>we&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 recon &amp;amp; tooling 6[84]43 week1 good faith policy We expect a high standard of professionalism from you at all times while you are taking any of our courses. We expect all students to act in good faith at all times
TLDR: Don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk
sec.edu.au/good-faith-policy
&amp;gt; whoami Lachlan how to contact me lachlan.waugh@student.unsw.edu.au @melon on the SecSoc Discord @melon on the SecEdu Slack (kinda dead) places for course discussion course information &amp;gt; course discussion on webcms secso.</description></item><item><title>10: advanced stuff</title><link>/week10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week10/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 idk 6[84]43 week10 Final exam Overview wednesday, 3rd May 3 hours (1pm - 4pm) worth 50% whats in it everything is assessable™ not just stuff from wargames submit a short writeup explaination there&amp;rsquo;s also a shortish devsecops question how2hack my biggest tip is try not to stress out + practice, practice, practice start with recon before you write payloads CI/CD keeping it secure github actions (ramble) pre-commit hooks .</description></item><item><title>2: auth</title><link>/week2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 authorization &amp;amp; authentication 6[84]43 week2 admin stuff challenges how are you finding this week&amp;rsquo;s challenges? for each set of challenges, I&amp;rsquo;ll say which I think you should try this week: all of them lol there&amp;rsquo;s some flags online that are old, ignore them points don&amp;rsquo;t indicate difficulty walkthroughs present your solution for some of the challenges only the harder ones (maybe some of files/blog) Reports what to talk about vulnerability details proof of concept / steps to Reproduce impact !</description></item><item><title>3: iam groot</title><link>/week3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 identity and access management 6[84]43 week3 Challenges From now on, all challenges are worth marks. From next week, the challenges are more difficult! We&amp;rsquo;ll say which challenges are required What&amp;rsquo;s coming up? wk4+5: server-side injection SQLi, SSI, XXE, SSRF, SSTI, file uploads wk7+8: client-side injection XSS, JSONP, Clickjacking, CSRF due dates topic2 challenges: THIS SUNDAY 11:59pm midterm: week5 monday report: week5 sunday 11:59pm reports any questions</description></item><item><title>4: ssi</title><link>/week4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 server-side injection 6[84]43 week4 SSTI (did they gggo through this? idk) Shell injection, RCE and Reverse Shells Upcoming due dates? next week
wed 6-7pm: mid-sem (10%) sun 11:59pm report01 (20%) topic03 challenges SQL Structured Query Language
SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL Server Fingerprinting
work out the flavour/version MySQL: Version() SQLite: sqlite_version() MSSQL: @@Version Finding the schema
what tables exist, what do they look like? MySQL: information_schema.[tables|columns] SQLite: sqlite_[master|schema] MSSQL: SHOW TABLES; DESCRIBE &amp;lt;table_name&amp;gt; Queries &amp;gt;</description></item><item><title>5: serverside</title><link>/week5/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week5/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 more server-side 6[84]43 week5 House cleaning Report groups If you aren&amp;rsquo;t in a group please let me know
Midterm How&amp;rsquo;d you all find it (trivial enough?)
Injection Bash Injection SSTI PHP Injection bash injection If you&amp;rsquo;re ever using os.system() (or similar) to call shell functions containing user input first of all, probably don&amp;rsquo;t second of all, it&amp;rsquo;s kinda vulnerable Demo SSTI (Server-side template injection) Templating engines (eg.</description></item><item><title>7: cs injection</title><link>/week7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week7/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 client side injection 6[84]43 week7 house cleaning due dates most of the Topic04 challenges should be out these are due Week8 Sunday @ 11:59pm report groups the second report is out if you need a new group for the 2nd report, msg me. marks/feedback will be out at some point origin vs site origin https://www.example.com:80
origin = scheme + host + port
origin vs site site http://www.</description></item><item><title>8: clientside</title><link>/week8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/week8/</guid><description>we&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 1[68]:05 client-side protections 6[84]43 week8 house cleaning due dates the rest of the topic04 challenges should be out they&amp;rsquo;re due sunday week9. reports (general feedback) consider context when determining impact, not everything is critical. keep technical stuff out of impact/remediation. It should mostly be in steps to reproduce. mitigating xss basic waf stuff
sanitisation: stripping out unsafe tags/attributes &amp;lt;script&amp;gt;alert(1)&amp;lt;script&amp;gt; → alert(1) encoding: escaping control characters &amp;lt;&amp;gt; → &amp;amp;lt;&amp;amp;gt; validation: allow/block-listing of content block requests if you detect bad content don&amp;rsquo;t use raw user input .</description></item><item><title>9: protections</title><link>/lectures/week9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/lectures/week9/</guid><description>client-side mitigations 6443 week9 Origin https://www.example.com:80
origin = scheme + host + port
Site http://www.example.com:80
https://api.example.com:443
site = private_domain + public_suffix
scheme, subdomain and port SOP (Same Origin Policy) blocks resource requests to/from an external site
&amp;ldquo;external&amp;rdquo; is based on sop: only requests from the same origin are allowed to use the resources
more secure but how people bypassed it isn&amp;rsquo;t xd
cross-origin resource sharing obviously sometimes you need to access resources from another origin (e.</description></item><item><title>x8: cs</title><link>/lectures/ext8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/lectures/ext8/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll get started at 18:05 client side attacks 6843 week8 overview how do browsers work? how can we exploit this mutation xss dom clobbering client-side js exploitation how do browsers work they render html, css, and js into the DOM
you can think of them kinda like an interpreters or a couple of interpreters (js + html parser) read more here
syntax errors what happens when a brower receives invalidly formatted content (js, html, css)?</description></item></channel></rss>